## **MOHINI RANA**

2147 Newhall Street, Santa Clara, CA - 95050 | 781.952.9913 | mrana@scu.edu | www.linkedin.com/mohini-rana

### **SUMMARY**

Machine Learning and Data Science enthusiast with 2+ years of experience using data pre-processing, predictive modeling with time series forecasting algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Proven skills in leading large teams, with a focus on optimizing development processes to enhance efficiency and accuracy for data-driven solutions.

## **EDUCATION**

Master's in Computer Science and Engineering | Santa Clara University, USA| GPA - 4/4 | 2021 - 2023 Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology) | University of Pune, India | GPA - 3.48/4 | 2015 - 2019

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Publishing Assistant, Miller Center for Social Entrepreneurship, Santa Clara, USA

Nov 2021 - Nov 2021

- I was responsible for assisting in creating books using the Bookwright software.
- I worked on helping the Miller Center team to create, design, and organize various pages of about 10-15 books.

## Associate Consultant - Data Scientist, Supply Chain Apps, Bristlecone, Pune, India

**July 2019 - Sept 2021** 

- Worked on writing algorithms in Python for demand forecasting using time series- VAR, Arima, Sarimax, Prophet, Holt-Winters, Naïve Bayes, writing other Machine Learning algorithms such as linear regression, logistic regression, k-means clustering, random forest for tasks involving the prediction of sales data.
- Gained hands-on experience in data pre-processing, data cleaning, and handling missing data.
- Worked on six POCs and was also responsible for carrying out extensive research-related activities involving competitor analysis, providing insights, and presenting my findings using Tableau and PowerPoint presentations.
- I was awarded for my contributions to my projects and also organizing events a Brilliant Beginner and two SPOT awards.

## ML Engineer Intern, DigitalMain, Pune, India

March 2018 - June 2019

- Worked as an active member of the team for the AI/ML Innovation Project.
- The tools and technology used were Semantic Text Analysis and using Deep Learning and Neural Networking.
- The project involved me to find a solution to one of the ongoing projects at DigitalMain. I had to build a working POC to reduce the redundancy of questions by creating a POC to identify similar questions.
- Carried out research in the domain, studied various concepts, and applied the knowledge to build the Similar Questions Identifier Model for DigitalMain, and published my findings in the IJRAR Journal. https://github.com/MohiniRana/My-Profile/blob/main/Survey%20Paper.pdf

## Business Analyst Intern in IT, Vidya Online Services, Pune, India

**July 2018 - Oct 2018** 

- Prepared documents like Business Requirement documents, Functional Requirement documents for clients, and applied knowledge of Software Development Life Cycle and Project Management.
- Created a User Manual Document for one of the clients for their website.

#### ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Similar Question Identifier using Deep Learning, Neural Networks in Python
- Lightweight Mutual Authentication for IOT & Its Applications using RSA and ECC
- Attendance Monitoring System website using HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Java
- Periodic Table using SQL and Java

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, C, C++, Java, Tableau, R Studio, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Canva, BookWright, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Word

### **AFFILIATIONS**

Held positions of Technical Secretary (2018-19), Technical Head (2017-18), and Discipline Head (2016-17) during College Fest Alacrity, Treasurer (2018 - 2019) of Dept. of IT Engg Dept, and was the General Secretary (2015-16) of First-Year Dept., and was Internshala Student Partner for 3 consecutive semesters (2018-2019)

## **INTERESTS**

Reading, playing table tennis, solving puzzles, learning new software tools to improve personal efficiency and effectiveness, volunteering, event management.